<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: &#8220;Cause he&#8217;s down by the pond playing hockey with the kids&#8230;&#8221;	</title>
	<atom:link href="https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/cause-hes-down-by-the-pond-playing-hockey-with-the-kids/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/cause-hes-down-by-the-pond-playing-hockey-with-the-kids/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 14:59:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Open Minded Observer		</title>
		<link>https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/cause-hes-down-by-the-pond-playing-hockey-with-the-kids/#comment-37</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Open Minded Observer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 14:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nanettedmassey.com/?p=192#comment-37</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thank you for sharing this story with your readers!
&quot;Chirping&quot; is considered part of the game in youth hockey and as you&#039;ve pointed out, teams are generally lacking in diversity (to put it mildly).  So, it&#039;s no surprise that racial slurs and mocking of the sort you&#039;ve described happen on the ice, on the bench and even in the locker room.  As you noted, local sanctioning bodies, officials and coaches are often ill equipped to deal with incidents and would prefer to remain safely in their White bubble and ignore issues.  

The good news is that&#039;s changing... slowly, but there has been progress.  Organizations and sanctioning bodies are adopting new policies and Coaches and officials are receiving training on those policies.  Everyone can still choose to sweep issues under the rug, but with a little advocating from the parents, everyone at least has procedures to follow and incidents will be recorded.

Organizations like Players Against Hate have been working with the NHL and USA Hockey to try and raise awareness and get policies and training in place.  Getting people to even acknowledge there&#039;s an issue was an uphill battle and recently USAH emailed every player and their parents a letter which highlighted the issue and outlined policy changes.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thank you for sharing this story with your readers!<br />
&#8220;Chirping&#8221; is considered part of the game in youth hockey and as you&#8217;ve pointed out, teams are generally lacking in diversity (to put it mildly).  So, it&#8217;s no surprise that racial slurs and mocking of the sort you&#8217;ve described happen on the ice, on the bench and even in the locker room.  As you noted, local sanctioning bodies, officials and coaches are often ill equipped to deal with incidents and would prefer to remain safely in their White bubble and ignore issues.  </p>
<p>The good news is that&#8217;s changing&#8230; slowly, but there has been progress.  Organizations and sanctioning bodies are adopting new policies and Coaches and officials are receiving training on those policies.  Everyone can still choose to sweep issues under the rug, but with a little advocating from the parents, everyone at least has procedures to follow and incidents will be recorded.</p>
<p>Organizations like Players Against Hate have been working with the NHL and USA Hockey to try and raise awareness and get policies and training in place.  Getting people to even acknowledge there&#8217;s an issue was an uphill battle and recently USAH emailed every player and their parents a letter which highlighted the issue and outlined policy changes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Ricardo		</title>
		<link>https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/cause-hes-down-by-the-pond-playing-hockey-with-the-kids/#comment-36</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ricardo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 18:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nanettedmassey.com/?p=192#comment-36</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nanette, I wish I would have read the article and your comments regarding a posting to your FB page. You have already began to accomplish what we spoke of a few months back. Getting paid is a good thing and bringing awareness and positive change does deserve its rightful reward.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nanette, I wish I would have read the article and your comments regarding a posting to your FB page. You have already began to accomplish what we spoke of a few months back. Getting paid is a good thing and bringing awareness and positive change does deserve its rightful reward.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Paul Harvey		</title>
		<link>https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/cause-hes-down-by-the-pond-playing-hockey-with-the-kids/#comment-35</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul Harvey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 15:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nanettedmassey.com/?p=192#comment-35</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nanette,

Thanks for your perspective on this recent incident. The silence of otherwise well intentioned &quot;good&quot; white people only serves to help prop up and maintain the oppressive system of white supremacy, as it has for 400 years now. Instead of thinking of our silence as simply &quot;keeping the peace&quot;,  we might want to consider the historical and ongoing trauma and violence our silence enables.

We all must push past our comfort zone in our pursuit of a truly liberated and just society. 

Thanks also for that amazing and very powerful presentation Saturday on the book White Fragility. You are a radical bridge building warrior woman! But this was seriously courageous, passionate, and heartfelt stuff. Thank you so much. Hopefully you&#039;re able to continue advancing this essential and groundbreaking work into the future.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nanette,</p>
<p>Thanks for your perspective on this recent incident. The silence of otherwise well intentioned &#8220;good&#8221; white people only serves to help prop up and maintain the oppressive system of white supremacy, as it has for 400 years now. Instead of thinking of our silence as simply &#8220;keeping the peace&#8221;,  we might want to consider the historical and ongoing trauma and violence our silence enables.</p>
<p>We all must push past our comfort zone in our pursuit of a truly liberated and just society. </p>
<p>Thanks also for that amazing and very powerful presentation Saturday on the book White Fragility. You are a radical bridge building warrior woman! But this was seriously courageous, passionate, and heartfelt stuff. Thank you so much. Hopefully you&#8217;re able to continue advancing this essential and groundbreaking work into the future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Paul		</title>
		<link>https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/cause-hes-down-by-the-pond-playing-hockey-with-the-kids/#comment-34</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Paul]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 14:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nanettedmassey.com/?p=192#comment-34</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hi Nanette, 

Thanks for this much needed perspective.  The silence of otherwise well meaning white people only helps prop up and maintain 400 years of white supremacy. Instead of thinking of our silence as noble efforts at &quot;keeping the peace&quot;, or maintaining optics of &quot;being nice&quot;, we might want to consider the awful emotional trauma being inflicted on a child. Merely by having dark skin. 

We all must push past our comfort zone in our pursuit of a truly liberated and just society.

Thanks also for that amazing and we&#039;ll put together presentation Saturday on White Fragility.  Truly courageous, passionate, and heartfelt stuff. Hopefully you can continue this essential, groundbreaking work far into the future!]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Nanette, </p>
<p>Thanks for this much needed perspective.  The silence of otherwise well meaning white people only helps prop up and maintain 400 years of white supremacy. Instead of thinking of our silence as noble efforts at &#8220;keeping the peace&#8221;, or maintaining optics of &#8220;being nice&#8221;, we might want to consider the awful emotional trauma being inflicted on a child. Merely by having dark skin. </p>
<p>We all must push past our comfort zone in our pursuit of a truly liberated and just society.</p>
<p>Thanks also for that amazing and we&#8217;ll put together presentation Saturday on White Fragility.  Truly courageous, passionate, and heartfelt stuff. Hopefully you can continue this essential, groundbreaking work far into the future!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Mara Koven-Gelman		</title>
		<link>https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/cause-hes-down-by-the-pond-playing-hockey-with-the-kids/#comment-33</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mara Koven-Gelman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 14:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nanettedmassey.com/?p=192#comment-33</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hi Nanette,
 This is excellent!!!! I love how you use White Fragility to examine and call out the racist actions of hockey league and those in the stands. In language of the Holocaust or other genocides, we say that it takes three people to allow a genocide to occur: the perpetrator, the victim and the bystander. You are noting that in the hockey racist event, the team mates and those in the stands were bystanders and equally guilty. Society has to encourage people to not be bystanders (there are a lot more of them, than victims and perpetrators.) Good luck on Saturday.
 
 Also – saw there is an adult ed series at the JCC Holland (on Delaware).Thought you’d like to see the title of the series. Maybe you can teach a class? Not sure if it is a paid gig? Name of staff is on banner.
 
 [cid:image005.jpg@01D50974.FAAF33A0][cid:image001.jpg@01D50974.FF38B360]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi Nanette,<br />
 This is excellent!!!! I love how you use White Fragility to examine and call out the racist actions of hockey league and those in the stands. In language of the Holocaust or other genocides, we say that it takes three people to allow a genocide to occur: the perpetrator, the victim and the bystander. You are noting that in the hockey racist event, the team mates and those in the stands were bystanders and equally guilty. Society has to encourage people to not be bystanders (there are a lot more of them, than victims and perpetrators.) Good luck on Saturday.</p>
<p> Also – saw there is an adult ed series at the JCC Holland (on Delaware).Thought you’d like to see the title of the series. Maybe you can teach a class? Not sure if it is a paid gig? Name of staff is on banner.</p>
<p> [cid:image005.jpg@01D50974.FAAF33A0][cid:image001.jpg@01D50974.FF38B360]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
