<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Letter from a Williamsville Church	</title>
	<atom:link href="https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/letter-from-a-williamsville-church/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/letter-from-a-williamsville-church/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 16:44:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.0.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Geraldine Wierzbicki-Roach		</title>
		<link>https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/letter-from-a-williamsville-church/#comment-32</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Geraldine Wierzbicki-Roach]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 16:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nanettedmassey.com/?p=173#comment-32</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nannette, I am new to your blog but I love and applaud it. You are a very gifted writer and thinker.I live in a senior apartment complex and have pondered the fact that only one black person lives here. This is an expensive place and I don&#039;t have to ponder too hard or too long to understand why. I want to be authentic. That means wherever I am tackle the issues. I will give it my damnedest. Thank you for kicking my ass.
Geraldine Wierzbicki-Rpach]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nannette, I am new to your blog but I love and applaud it. You are a very gifted writer and thinker.I live in a senior apartment complex and have pondered the fact that only one black person lives here. This is an expensive place and I don&#8217;t have to ponder too hard or too long to understand why. I want to be authentic. That means wherever I am tackle the issues. I will give it my damnedest. Thank you for kicking my ass.<br />
Geraldine Wierzbicki-Rpach</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Howard&#8217;s Way &#8211; Nanette D. Massey		</title>
		<link>https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/letter-from-a-williamsville-church/#comment-31</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Howard&#8217;s Way &#8211; Nanette D. Massey]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 07:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nanettedmassey.com/?p=173#comment-31</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[[&#8230;] about Martin Luther King Day. I talked about MLK’s Letter From A Birmingham Jail. In it, the icon expressed his disappointment that the southern towns’ white religious institutions weren’t emptying their pews to support [&#8230;]]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>[&#8230;] about Martin Luther King Day. I talked about MLK’s Letter From A Birmingham Jail. In it, the icon expressed his disappointment that the southern towns’ white religious institutions weren’t emptying their pews to support [&#8230;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Meg Doerzbacher		</title>
		<link>https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/letter-from-a-williamsville-church/#comment-30</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Meg Doerzbacher]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 01:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nanettedmassey.com/?p=173#comment-30</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nanette, it would be an honor and privilege to be called one of your allies! - Meg D.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nanette, it would be an honor and privilege to be called one of your allies! &#8211; Meg D.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Pat Burke		</title>
		<link>https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/letter-from-a-williamsville-church/#comment-29</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Pat Burke]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 01:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nanettedmassey.com/?p=173#comment-29</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nannette
Thanks for your blog and jogging our minds to continue to work toward  better relationships with our black brothers and sisters.  Our food pantry is keeping  us busy, but we need to keep learning how we can improve and make life better for All.  You keep me focused on what is important and inspire me to improve.  Thank you Nanette]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nannette<br />
Thanks for your blog and jogging our minds to continue to work toward  better relationships with our black brothers and sisters.  Our food pantry is keeping  us busy, but we need to keep learning how we can improve and make life better for All.  You keep me focused on what is important and inspire me to improve.  Thank you Nanette</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Christine Ellington		</title>
		<link>https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/letter-from-a-williamsville-church/#comment-28</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Ellington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2019 01:58:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nanettedmassey.com/?p=173#comment-28</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In reply to &lt;a href=&quot;https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/letter-from-a-williamsville-church/#comment-26&quot;&gt;Christine Ellington&lt;/a&gt;.

Wow!  I read your blog and can&#039;t help but go ahhh!
I didn&#039;t know much of the information you wrote about in your blog.
Your blog certainly makes me think about the word &quot;relationship&quot; and 
think dinner evenings can be a movement of its own.

Christine Ellington]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In reply to <a href="https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/letter-from-a-williamsville-church/#comment-26">Christine Ellington</a>.</p>
<p>Wow!  I read your blog and can&#8217;t help but go ahhh!<br />
I didn&#8217;t know much of the information you wrote about in your blog.<br />
Your blog certainly makes me think about the word &#8220;relationship&#8221; and<br />
think dinner evenings can be a movement of its own.</p>
<p>Christine Ellington</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Sanjay Sathe		</title>
		<link>https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/letter-from-a-williamsville-church/#comment-27</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sanjay Sathe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 03:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nanettedmassey.com/?p=173#comment-27</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nanette, As always interesting and thought provoking. 

It is interesting that in India in 1920&#039;s there were many including many Indians who criticized Gandhi for his actions arguing that more progress could be made through the Constitutional process than through civil disobedience. After 70 plus years of independence I personally think that the Constitutionalist have the better argument. However, everybody needs a hero - and most Indians would prefer to think that Gandhi won independence - rather than think of independence as inevitable.(2.5million Indians fought for the Allies in WW2 and there were only 50,000 white British troops in India),  I suspect that the same is true about civil rights in the US. Having said that I think there is a world of difference between MLK and Gandhi. Gandhi IMO was a hypocrite - he claimed the mantle of non violence but in fact his tactics succeeded precisely because they threatened violence- what else was a hunger fast to death but the threat of violence that would result from his death. MLK on the other hand was truly non-violent. There was no threat of violence in his actions- they were solely to appeal to the moral conscience of a nation. 

The state of the black community in 50&#039;s and 60&#039;s is completely different to what it is today. I did some googling - in 2016 there 7,000 blacks who were victims of homicide. 215 of them were killed by white people. Unlike the 50s and 60&#039;s if you are black person going about your business you are more likely to be killed by a black person than you are by a white person. While police shootings of black men understandably  get all the attention- the reality is that even if there were zero killings of black men by police - it would not be noticeable in the homicide statistics. I think the &quot;blacks lives matter&quot; movement distracts from (a) the more serious threat to black lives why is it that we have no outrage for a black child killed in a drive by but so much for knife carrying black man shot by the police ? It seems that it reflects the worst kind of racism - we accept that that blacks will kill each other but expect more from a white man ! and (b) the daily humiliation that people of color suffer. 

On Thu, Jan 31, 2019 at 2:42 AM Nanette D. Massey  wrote: 

&#062; Nanette D. Massey posted: &quot;For nine days in 1963 the revered Reverend Dr. &#062; Martin Luther King was jailed in Birmingham, Alabama, charged with parading &#062; without a license. He had been called to the city by the Southern Christian &#062; Leadership Conference to bring media attention to a sust&quot; &#062;]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Nanette, As always interesting and thought provoking. </p>
<p>It is interesting that in India in 1920&#8217;s there were many including many Indians who criticized Gandhi for his actions arguing that more progress could be made through the Constitutional process than through civil disobedience. After 70 plus years of independence I personally think that the Constitutionalist have the better argument. However, everybody needs a hero &#8211; and most Indians would prefer to think that Gandhi won independence &#8211; rather than think of independence as inevitable.(2.5million Indians fought for the Allies in WW2 and there were only 50,000 white British troops in India),  I suspect that the same is true about civil rights in the US. Having said that I think there is a world of difference between MLK and Gandhi. Gandhi IMO was a hypocrite &#8211; he claimed the mantle of non violence but in fact his tactics succeeded precisely because they threatened violence- what else was a hunger fast to death but the threat of violence that would result from his death. MLK on the other hand was truly non-violent. There was no threat of violence in his actions- they were solely to appeal to the moral conscience of a nation. </p>
<p>The state of the black community in 50&#8217;s and 60&#8217;s is completely different to what it is today. I did some googling &#8211; in 2016 there 7,000 blacks who were victims of homicide. 215 of them were killed by white people. Unlike the 50s and 60&#8217;s if you are black person going about your business you are more likely to be killed by a black person than you are by a white person. While police shootings of black men understandably  get all the attention- the reality is that even if there were zero killings of black men by police &#8211; it would not be noticeable in the homicide statistics. I think the &#8220;blacks lives matter&#8221; movement distracts from (a) the more serious threat to black lives why is it that we have no outrage for a black child killed in a drive by but so much for knife carrying black man shot by the police ? It seems that it reflects the worst kind of racism &#8211; we accept that that blacks will kill each other but expect more from a white man ! and (b) the daily humiliation that people of color suffer. </p>
<p>On Thu, Jan 31, 2019 at 2:42 AM Nanette D. Massey  wrote: </p>
<p>&gt; Nanette D. Massey posted: &#8220;For nine days in 1963 the revered Reverend Dr. &gt; Martin Luther King was jailed in Birmingham, Alabama, charged with parading &gt; without a license. He had been called to the city by the Southern Christian &gt; Leadership Conference to bring media attention to a sust&#8221; &gt;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Christine Ellington		</title>
		<link>https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/letter-from-a-williamsville-church/#comment-26</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Christine Ellington]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nanettedmassey.com/?p=173#comment-26</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I think you are the right person to assist the Williamsville Church.  You have the realness to enrich the fabric of America&#039;s values.  We&#039;re, all of us, from somewhere else and we need to be joined together with heart and head to make change.  I am still trying to figure out how to participate in being a change agent and your blog is helping me to learn of actions to consider.  You have encouraged me to take a step beyond thought to action with the information you shared.  Thank you for sharing.

Keep writing!  

Christine Ellington]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I think you are the right person to assist the Williamsville Church.  You have the realness to enrich the fabric of America&#8217;s values.  We&#8217;re, all of us, from somewhere else and we need to be joined together with heart and head to make change.  I am still trying to figure out how to participate in being a change agent and your blog is helping me to learn of actions to consider.  You have encouraged me to take a step beyond thought to action with the information you shared.  Thank you for sharing.</p>
<p>Keep writing!  </p>
<p>Christine Ellington</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>
		By: Mara Koven-Gelman		</title>
		<link>https://samj921.github.io/nanettedmassey/letter-from-a-williamsville-church/#comment-25</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mara Koven-Gelman]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 18:21:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nanettedmassey.com/?p=173#comment-25</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thank you Nanette for another enlightening, honest blog post. You remind us of Rev. MLK Jr. impactful words and historical context. Much work as to be done.  The Jewish community
looks forward to deeper discussion about race and justice. I&#039;ll share your post with the Jewish Community Relations Council Exec. Committee.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Thank you Nanette for another enlightening, honest blog post. You remind us of Rev. MLK Jr. impactful words and historical context. Much work as to be done.  The Jewish community<br />
looks forward to deeper discussion about race and justice. I&#8217;ll share your post with the Jewish Community Relations Council Exec. Committee.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
